artofmemory.com 2019-04-17

# privacy | Art of Memory, Inc.

Art of Memory Inc. **("Company," "we," or "us")** respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through this Privacy Policy.

The Art of Memory Network **("Network," or "Websites")** is a set of related Internet websites, online communities, and other applications about the practice and use of memory techniques, owned and operated by Art of Memory Inc. **("Company," "we," or "us")**. We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it through this Privacy Policy, which describes what information we collect on our Network and through the use of our products and services.

This Privacy Policy governs your access to and use of our Network, including any content, functionality, products, and services offered on or through the **Websites** , whether as a guest or a registered user.

When accessing the Websites, the Company will learn certain information about you, both automatically and through voluntary actions you may take, during your visit. This policy applies to information we collect on the Websites and in email, text, or other electronic messages between you and the Websites.

Please read the Privacy Policy carefully before you start to use the Websites. **By using the Websites or by clicking to accept or agree to the Terms of Use when this option is made available to you, you accept and agree to be bound and abide by the Privacy Policy.** If you do not want to agree to the Privacy Policy, you must not access or use the Websites.

## Children Under The Age Of 13

Our Websites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to or on the Websites. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on these Websites or on or through any of its features/register on the Websites, make any purchases through the Websites, use any of the interactive or public comment features of these Websites or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use.

If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

If you are in the European Union, you must be at least 16 years old to access our Websites. If you access or use our Websites, you represent and warrant that you are at least 16 years of age. If you are under 16 years old, you are not allowed to access or use our Websites in any manner and you, and you are not allowed to provide any personal information, such as, but not limited to, a name, address, telephone number, or email address).

## Information We Collect About You

When you access the Websites, the Company will learn certain information about you during your visit.

_Information You Provide To Us._ The Websites provide various places for users to provide information. We collect information that users provide by filling out forms on the Websites, communicating with us via contact forms, responding to surveys, search queries on our search feature, providing comments or other feedback, and providing information when ordering a product or service via the Websites.

We use information you provide to us to deliver the requested product and/or service, to improve our overall performance, and to provide you with offers, promotions, and information.

_Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technology._ As you navigate through our Websites, we may use automatic data collection technologies including Google Analytics to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns. This will generally include information about your location, your traffic pattern through our website, and any communications between your computer and our Websites.Among other things, we will collect data about the type of computer you use, your Internet connection, your IP address, your operating system, and your browser type.

The information we collect automatically is used for statistical data and will not include personal information. We use this data to improve our Websites and our service offerings. To the extent that you voluntarily provide personal information to us, our systems will associate the automatically collected information with your personal information.

## Use of Cookies And Pixels

Similar to other commercial websites, our website utilizes a standard technology called "cookies" and server logs to collect information about how our site is used. Information gathered through cookies and server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our site, and the websites visited just before and just after our own, as well as your IP address.

A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site's computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

The Company reserves the right to use technological equivalents of cookies, including social media pixels. These pixels allow social media sites to track visitors to outside websites so as to tailor advertising messages users see while visiting that social media website. The Company reserves the right to use these pixels in compliance with the policies of the various social media sites.

## Third Party Use Of Cookies

Some content or applications, including advertisements, on the Websites are served by third-parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and application providers. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use our website. The information they collect may be associated with your personal information or they may collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content.

We do not control these third parties' tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly.

## Email Information

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received online, mail, and telephone. This also applies when you register for our website, sign up through any of our forms using your email address or make a purchase on this site. For further information see the email policies below.

## Email Policies

We are committed to keeping your email address confidential. We do not sell, rent, or lease our subscription lists to third parties, and will not disclose your email address to any third parties except as allowed in the section titled Disclosure of Your Information.

We will maintain the information you send via email in accordance with applicable federal law.

In compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act, all emails sent from our organization will clearly state who the email is from and provide clear information on how to contact the sender. In addition, all email messages will also contain concise information on how to remove yourself from our mailing list so that you receive no further email communication from us.

Our emails provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners by reading the unsubscribe instructions located at the bottom of any email they receive from us at anytime.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials may opt-out of receiving these communications by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the email.

## How And Why We Collect Information

The Company collects your information in order to record and support your participation in the activities you select. In many cases, you can choose what information to provide. However, we sometimes require you to provide certain personal information in order to provide services and products. For example, you will need to provide your email address in order to register for the Websites and use certain products and services.

Use of certain products and services of the Network may require creating an account, for which you may need to provide a username associated with your account, an email address at which we can contact you, and possibly a password to help secure your personal information. If you purchase a product or service, additional information such as a billing address may be required. When registering for an account with the Network, you can use an anonymous or pseudonymous username to maintain your privacy.

During the account registration process, some of the information you provide, both required and optional, will appear publicly in your account profile. For example, your username and, if you choose to do so, any information you provide in certain optional fields in your account profile will be publicly visible.

If you create an account to use our products or services, such as using our software and participating in our online community, register to download a book or resources, sign up for our newsletter, and/or purchase a product from us, we collect your information. We use this information to track your preferences and to keep you informed about the products and services you have selected to receive and any related products and/or services. As a visitor to these Websites, you can engage in most activities without providing any personal information. It is only when you seek to download resources and/or register for services that you are required to provide information.

If you are outside the European Union and opt to receive any free resources, participate in any free training programs, register for a webinar, register for a live event, register for a seminar, or purchase any products sold by the Company on these Websites, we will automatically enroll you to receive our free email newsletter. If you do not wish to receive this newsletter, you can unsubscribe anytime. We include an "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of every email we send. If you ever have trouble unsubscribing, you can send an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) requesting to unsubscribe from future emails.

If you are in the European Union and opt to receive any free resources, participate in any free training programs, register for a webinar, register for a live event, register for a seminar, or purchase any products sold by the Company on these Websites, we will only enroll you to receive our free email newsletter if you affirmatively consent to it. If you do not wish to receive this newsletter, you can unsubscribe anytime. We include an "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of every email we send. If you ever have trouble unsubscribing, you can send an email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) requesting to unsubscribe from future emails.

## How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?

We use personal information for purposes of presenting our Websites and its contents to you, providing you with information, providing you with offers for products and services, providing you with information about your subscriptions and products, carrying out any contract between you and the Company, administering our business activities, providing customer service, and making available other items and services to our customers and prospective customers.

From time-to-time, we may use the information you provide to us to make you offers to purchase products and services provided by third parties in exchange for a commission to be paid to us by such third parties. Should you opt to take part in such promotions, the third parties will receive your information.

From time-to-time, we may use the information you provide to us to display advertisements to you that are tailored to your personal characteristics, interests, and activities.

## Disclosure Of Your Information

As a general rule, we do not sell, rent, lease or otherwise transfer any information collected whether automatically or through your voluntary action.

We may disclose your personal information to our subsidiaries, affiliates, and service providers for the purpose of providing our services to you.

We may disclose your personal information to a third party, including a lawyer or collection agency, when necessary to enforce our terms of service or any other agreement between you and the Company.

We may provide your information to any successor in interest in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of the Company's assets and/or business.

We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights or when compelled by a court or other governmental entity to do so.

## How Do We Protect Your Information and Secure Information Transmissions?

We employ commercially reasonable methods to ensure the security of the information you provide to us and the information we collect automatically. This includes using standard security protocols and working only with reputable third-party vendors.

Email is not recognized as a secure medium of communication. For this reason, we request that you do not send private information to us by email. However, doing so is allowed, but at your own risk. Some of the information you may enter on our website may be transmitted securely via a secure medium known as Secure Sockets Layer, or SSL. Credit Card information and other sensitive information is never transmitted via email.

The Company may use software programs to create summary statistics, which are used for such purposes as assessing the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas.

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, the Company uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

## Policy Changes

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. If we make material changes to how we treat our users' personal information, we will notify you by email to the email address specified in your account and/or through a notice on the Website home pages. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the bottom of the page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and deliverable email address for you, and for periodically visiting our Websites and this privacy policy to check for any changes.

## Visitors' GDPR Rights

If you are within the European Union, you are entitled to certain information and have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation. Those rights include:

We will retain the any information you choose to provide to us until the earlier of: (a) you asking us to delete the information, (b) our decision to cease using our existing data providers, or (c) the Company decides that the value in retaining the data is outweighed by the costs of retaining it.

You have the right to request access to your data that the Company stores and the rights to either rectify or erase your personal data.

You have the right to seek restrictions on the processing of your data.

You have the right to object to the processing of your data and the right to the portability of your data.

To the extent that you provided consent to the Company's processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based upon consent that occurred prior to your withdrawal of consent.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority that has jurisdiction over issues related to the General Data Protection Regulation.

We require only the information that is reasonably required to enter into a contract with you. We will not require you to provide consent for any unnecessary processing as a condition of entering into a contract with us.

## Contact Us

The Company welcomes your questions or comments regarding the Privacy Policy:

Art of Memory Inc.  
P.O. Box 20311  
El Sobrante, CA 94820

Email Address: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Effective as of June 5, 2018
